## JAGADEESHWARA CHANDRA BOSE.K

# **Electrical and Electronics Engineering**

|Jatayujagadeesh@gmail.com | | <u>LinkedIn</u>|

Industry Preference: Automotive Tenali, AndhraPradesh-522201.

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE:**

A passionate **Electrical & Electronics Engineer** aiming a professional environment to enrich my skills in the field of Design. I would be able to deliver the best of my knowledge by utilizing the skills and the experience I had fruitfully gained, to design, implement and contribute towards the new technologies.

#### **INTERNSHIPS:**

APOSIS SOLUTIONS - Bangalore

[08-04-2022 to 08-06-2022]

|| (+91)9705233003.||

APOSIS SOLUTIONS - Associated with TECHNICHE IIT GUWAHATI

Project - Development of Model for Motor Power & Suspension System of Electric Vehicle using Simulink.

PROJECTS:

## B.Tech Final year Major Project:

Collaborated on the Major project "Modeling and simulation of the complete electric power train of a Hybrid electric vehicle" with Associate professor Mr.Devireddy Tirupathi rao garu. The project aimed at designing a system that supplies constant DC power into 3-phase AC power in different modes of operation and interfaces all the power sources to Permanent Magnet Synchronous Motor.

- Designed a **2-Level Voltage Source Inverter**. The VSI Converts DC-AC 3-Phase.
- Designed the **SVPWM controller**.
- B.Tech Final year Mini Project:

Collaborated on the Mini project "High-Power Bidirectional DC-DC Converter for AerospaceApplications" MATLAB / Simulation, with Associate professor Mr. Shaker Babu garu. The project aimed at designing a system that supplies constant power to the switching into different modes of operation and interfaces all the power loads via a DC/DC converter.

#### Diploma Final year Mini Project:

"Simulation and Design of Battery for EV Applications" using MATLAB Simulation The project aimedon Battery Management System (BMS) at different motor applications.

## Diploma Final year Major Project:

"Voltage source based on AC-DC converters" using MATLAB/Simulation, The project aimed on various function of Power Electronics and different switching characteristics.

## **INTERNSHIP:**

Organization: ANDHRA PRADESH POWER GENERATION CORPORATION LIMITED

Plant : Vijayawada Thermal Power Station. 5\*210 KV & 500 Megawatts

Designation: Industrial Internship Trainee

Work place : 440KV Substation, Power Transformers, Battery chamber, Conveyers

Grade : Good.



## EDUCATION:

- Bachelor of Technology in Electrical & Electronics Engineering, JNTUK- St. Mary's group of institutions, Andhra Pradesh with aggregate CGPA of 6.8 in the year 2019-2022.
- Diploma in Electrical & Electronics Engineering, St. Mary's group of institutions. AndhraPradesh with aggregate CGPA of 71.20 in the year 2015-2018.
- Secondary School of Education, SRS Municipal Boys high school, Andhra Pradesh with aggregate CGPA of 7.8 in the year 2015.

# **EXPERIENCE:**

## ASSISTANT ENGINEER, AMARARAJA BATTERIES LIMITED, Chittoor - A.P.

IBD-Industrial Battery Division -- MVRLA-Medium Value Regulated Lead Acid Battery

Department : (ELECTRICAL TESTNG LAB – QUALITY ASSURANCE)

Functional area: (BMS) - Battery management system.

Duration : 21- August-2019 to 23-October- 2020.

# Responsibilities:

- Electrical Testing Analysis Lab. (Discharge process Compliance Test, Life Cycle Test)
- Manual Testing and Auto Testing.
- Data logger data reports
- Tear Down Analysis Lab and Field return Analysis.
- Analysis of failure in battery pack troubleshooting and preparing daily report.
- Identifying root cause analysis using the data acquisition.
- Customer Inspections Railway's, RITES, and Process Engineering, Internal Inspections.

## RELEVANT SKILLS:

* Linux Systems	* C – programming	* MATLAB-Simulation
RELEVANT SKILLS:		
* Facility Management	* Analysis Safety Permit	* Attention to Detail
* Creative Thinker	* Auditing Skills	* Machinery Utilization
* Technical Proceedings	* Documentation	* Time management

# POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITY AND SOCIAL WORK

## NATIONAL CADET CORPS [NCC], 22Andhra Bn, Tenali – Andhrapradesh.

2012-2014

**AMARA RAJA** 

- NCC-"A" with certificate rank holder
- All INDIA TREKKING EXPEDITION AP TREK 2013 Camp Tirupathi, Andharpradesh, India.
- Annual Training Camp Tenali, Andhrapradesh, India.
- President of the School Student Body for two consecutive years of SMGIG.
- Former head of Public Relation & cultural committee in Student Active Council of SMGIG.